A Guide to the Peter Hoy Collection, ca. 1968-ca. 1989
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Peter Hoy Collection ca. 1968-ca. 1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10870-d
This collection consists of eleven items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was received as a gift on November 22, 1989.
Contents List
- Manuscripts 1968-1970
  - Poems by Nicholas Moore (1918-1986) ca. 1968-1969, 7 TMs poems, fourteen pages.
    Nicholas Moore was the English poet associated with the Apocalypse Group in the forties. These poems include "Badgering," "The Black Swan's Shadow," "Of the World as a Glove," "The Smirks of Snarl Marx," "Eu- Katatastrophe," "If I Were A Bent-Head," and "Last Chill and Testament."
  - Poem "Young Swans by Ditton Towpath" by Nicholas Moore ca. 1968-1969, TMs.
    The poem is written on an envelope, two pages, with handwritten annotations, sent to Hoy as a response to a series of postcard poems Hoy published as Fishpaste.
  - Poem "The Hands of Jeanne-Marie" by Arthur Rimbaud (1854-1891) 1969 [September 4 ?], TMs, two pages.
    Rimbaud was a French poet and member of the Symbolists. The poem was translated from the French by Alan Bold (1943- ), the Scottish poet, critic and translator, and accompanies a letter from Bold to Hoy, September 4, 1969.
  - Poems "100 Hats" and "Dumb" by Dannie Abse (1923- ) ca. 1969, TMs.
    Abse is a Welsh poet; these poems were translated by Alan Bold.
  - Poems taken from Versions From Holderlin Volume II: What I Ownca. 1970, 7 TMs Poems, six pages.
    These poems were translated by John Riley (1937-1978) and Tim Longville and published by Grosseteste Press in the Autumn of 1970.
- Letters 1969
  - Tim Longville to Peter Hoy 1969 September 3, ALS, one page.
    Thanks Hoy for the copy of the magazine Notebooks of Pierre Menard, which he goes on to critique, including the contents of the magazine, the typeface, cover, and the quality of the translations, including his own translations of the German poet, Friedrich Holderlin (1770-1843).
  - Alan Bold to Peter Hoy 1969 September 4, TNS, one page.
    Gives Hoy permission to use his translation of Arthur Rimbaud's poem, "The Hands of Jeanne-Marie" whenever and however he chooses, provided he sends him a copy.
  - Tim Longville to Peter Hoy 1969 September 6, TLS, two pages.
    Informs Hoy of his progress in translating foreign poetry, especially Holderlin, criticizes the translations of Friedrich Holderlin done by Herr Beckmann as full of misinterpretations, omissions, and misleading translations, and criticizes the accuracy of the Penguin edition of Holderlin's poems by Michael Hamburger, with many examples of inaccuracies.
  - Ted Walker to Peter Hoy 1969 September 11, APCS, one page.
    The English poet Walker (1934- ) gives permission to publish a translation of a poem in The Notebooks of Pierre Menard, edited by Anthony Rudolf and Peter Hoy, issue no. 8, April 15, 1970, but asks Hoy to also request permission from his publisher, Cape Poetry Paperbacks, who will publish the same poem in his new book The Night Bathers.
  - Alan Bold to Peter Hoy 1969 December [9?], TPCS, one page.
    Thanks him for both The Journals and The Notebooks of Pierre Menard, shares his enjoyment of the Patrick Bridgewater number (No. 3, German Poetry of the 1914-1918 War), and expresses delight that Hoy wants to publish a number of his own translations, furnishing several suggestions of possible poems to include, and mentions his book The State of the Nation.
- Printed Material 1989
  - "In My View" an article in The Sunday Times1989 October 22, Newsclipping.
    This article was written by Alan Bold concerning Scottish writers.